Nanbo Li

Ph.D. | The University of Edinburgh

L: +44 (0)7599878917 | ■: linanbo2008@gmail.com

A: nanboli.github.io | in: li-nanbo-424131135 | : wa2S80EAAAAJ

Research Interests

I am generally interested in probabilistic machine learning, causality, and computer vision, particularly generative models and causal representation learning. My PhD focused on developing machine learning models that learn to disentangle spurious correlations and identify modular generative structures within data, thus enabling interventional reasoning [1-4]. As my research closely connects to multiple well-established AI/ML/CV topics like world models [1-3,5], uncertainty estimation [1,7], and visual scene understanding [1-4], I am also excited about researching fundamental problems in these areas and their broad applications in healthcare, finance, and physics.

EDUCATION

The University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, UK

Ph.D. in Machine Learning and Computer Vision

2018-2022

- Thesis Title: Generative Factorization For Object-Centric Representation Learning

- Supervisors: Prof. Robert B. Fisher (principal) and Prof. Chris Williams (second)

The University of Edinburgh

Edinburgh, UK

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence (with Distinction)

2016-2017

Wuhan University of Technology

Wuhan, China

B.Eng. in Automation Engineering (Outstanding Engineer)

2012-2016

Work Experience

Research Intern

Zurich, Switzerland

Facebook Reality Labs

Research Intern
NEC Laboratories America. Inc

San Jose, CA, USA Summer 2021

Researcher/Engineer

 $UK \ \mathcal{E}. \ EU$

Trimbot2020 (European Union Horizon 2020 Programme)

2018-2020

Fall 2021

Research Assistant

Edinburgh, UK

Prof. Fisher's Computer Vision Lab at The University of Edinburgh

2017-2018

SKILLS

- Expertise: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Generative Models, Causal Representation Learning
- Software: Python, Linux, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Matlab, C++, Blender
- Language: English, Chinese (Mandarin)

SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

School of Informatics Scholarship

Edinburgh, UK

School of Informatics, The University of Edinburgh

2018

PUBLICATIONS

- Learning Object-Centric Representations of Multi-Object Scenes from Multiple Views Li Nanbo, Cian Eastwood, Robert B. Fisher Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020 (Spotlight, top 4%)
- Object-Centric Representation Learning with Generative Spatial-Temporal Factorization Li Nanbo, Muhammad Ahmed Raza, Hu Wenbin, Zhaole Sun, Robert B. Fisher Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021
- Duplicate Latent Representation Suppression for Multi-Object Variational Autoencoders Li Nanbo, Robert B. Fisher The British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2021
- Align-Deform-Subtract: An Interventional Framework for Explaining Object Differences
 Cian Eastwood^{1†}, Li Nanbo^{1†}, CKI Williams
 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) Workshop: Objects, Structure and Causality, 2022
- 5. Controllable Video Generation by Learning the Underlying Dynamical System with Neural ODE Yucheng Xu, Li Nanbo, Arushi Goel, Zijian Guo, Zonghai Yao, Hamidreza Kasaei, Mohammadreze Kasaei, Zhibin Li arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.05323, 2023
- 6. Hybrid Multi-Camera Visual Servoing to Moving Target Hanz Cuevas-Velasquez^{1†}, Nanbo Li^{1†}, Radim Tylecek, Marcelo Saval-Calvo, Robert B. Fisher IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2018
- DUGMA: Dynamic Uncertainty-Based Gaussian Mixture Alignment Can Pu, Nanbo Li, Radim Tylecek, Robert B. Fisher International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2018 (Oral presentation)
- SDF-MAN: Semi-Supervised Disparity Fusion with Multi-Scale Adversarial Networks
 Can Pu, Runzi Song, Radim Tylecek, Nanbo Li, Robert B Fisher
 Remote Sensing, 2019